Preliminary Inventory to the Russia. Konsul'stvo (Leipzig, Germany) Records, 1830-1914
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Konsul'stvo (Leipzig, Germany) Records,
1830-1914
34001
Russia. Konsul'stvo (Leipzig, Germany)
7 manuscript boxes (2.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, and printed matter, relating to Russian-German relations, especially commercial relations
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1934.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Germany; Germany--Commerce--Russia; Germany--Foreign relations--Russia; Leipzig (Germany); Russia; Russia--Commerce--Germany; Russia--Foreign relations--Germany
Container List
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1830-37
  - 1843-49
  - 1850-55
  - 1856-57
  - 1858-59 (Box 2)
  - 1860-63
  - 1865-67
  - 1868
  - 1870-71
  - 1872 (Box 3)
  - 1873
  - 1874
  - 1875-76
- Reports to the Foreign Office in St. Petersbug concerning the Fairs of Leipzig
  - 1878-1883
  - 1888
  - 1890-92
- Information on the Fairs of Leipzig, 1898, 1905 (Box 4)
- Reports of the Consulate on industrial and commerical questions
  - 1893-94
  - 1895-96
  - 1899
  - 1905, 1908-09
- Commerical reports, 1892
- Correspondence concerning industrial and commercial questions
  - 1893-95
  - 1902
  - 1906-09
  - 1910-11 (Box 5)
  - 1912-14
- Commerce conditions, 1901
- International exhibitions and meetings, 1883-1911
- Reports concerning Russia's commerce abroad, 1908, 1910-11
- Survey of the Fairs of Charkow, 1908-09
- Survey of the Fairs of Irbit
  - 1908
  - 1911-12
- Reports of the Stock Exchange at Charkow, 1910
- Peasant Home Industry in Russia and Germany, 1906, 1910-11, 1914
- Import of Russian grain to Saxony, 1889
- Industry in Saxony, 1898-99
- Commerce Divisions, 1899, 1903
- Commerce and Industry Divisions, 1880, 1890-1913
- Import of Russian geese to Germany, 1902
- Consulate service, 1890, 1906 (Box 6)
- Reports on polical questions, 1894
- Emperor Alexander III's death, 1894
- Consulate operations reports, 1906, 1908, 1910
- Consulate personal service and its drawing accounts, 1898-99, 1911
- Sanitary and veterinary (quarantine) questions, 1892, 1900
- Court and judicial questions, Convention on successions, 1890, 1900, 1906, 1913
- Agricultural and other workers, 1898, 1901-02
- Passports, 1894, 1907
- Student organizations and schools, 1900, 1908
- Consulate archives and library, 1900
- Russo-German societies, 1905
- Nationality, subjection, etc., 1911
- Charity and assistance, 1877-1912
- Foreign Office abroad reorganization, 1910-11
- Foreign Office consular service circulars (Box 7)
  - 1860-1881
  - 1882-89
  - 1890-92
  - 1893-99
  - 1901-02
  - 1903-06
  - 1907-1910
  - 1911
  - 1912
  - 1913-14